<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MainActivity</string>
    <string name="norway">Norway, officially the Kingdom of Norway, is a Scandinavian unitary constitutional monarchy whose territory comprises the western portion of the Scandinavian Peninsula, Jan Mayen, the Arctic archipelago of Svalbard, and the sub-Antarctic Bouvet Island. Norway has a total area of 385,252 square kilometres (148,747 sq mi) and a population of a little above 5 million. It is the 2nd least densely populated country in Europe. The country shares a long eastern border with Sweden (1,619 km or 1,006 mi long), which is the longest uninterrupted border within both Scandinavia and Europe at large. Norway is bordered by Finland and Russia to the north-east, and the Skagerrak Strait to the south, with Denmark on the other side. It shares maritime borders with Russia by the Barents Sea; Greenland, the Faroe Islands, and Iceland by the Norwegian Sea; and Sweden, Denmark, and the United Kingdom by the North Sea. Norway\'s extensive coastline, facing the North Atlantic Ocean and the Barents Sea, is laced with fjords, a renowned part of its landscape. The capital city Oslo is the largest in the nation, with a population of 650 thousand. Norway has extensive reserves of petroleum, natural gas, minerals, lumber, seafood, fresh water, and hydropower.\n
        Two centuries of Viking raids to southern and western areas tapered off following the adoption of Christianity in AD 994. Norway expanded its control overseas to parts of Britain, Ireland, Iceland, and Greenland. Norwegian power peaked in 1265, but competition from the Hanseatic League and the spread of the Black Death weakened the country. In 1380, Norway was absorbed into a union with Denmark that lasted more than four centuries. In 1814, Norwegians resisted the cession of their country to Sweden and adopted a constitution. Sweden went to war with Norway but agreed to let Norway keep its constitution in return for accepting the union under a Swedish king. Later Norway demanded independence, which it gained in a referendum in 1905. Norway remained neutral in World War I. Despite its declaration of neutrality in World War II, Norway was occupied for 5 years by forces of Nazi Germany. In 1949 it abandoned neutrality, becoming a founding member of NATO. Discovery of oil in adjacent waters in the late 1960s boosted Norway\'s economic fortunes. The country maintains a welfare model with universal health care, subsidised higher education, and a comprehensive social security system. Key domestic issues include maintaining the country\'s extensive social safety net with an aging population and preserving economic competitiveness. The petroleum industry accounts for around a quarter of the country\'s gross domestic product.\n
        King Harald V is Norway\'s head of state and Erna Solberg became Prime Minister on 16 October 2013, replacing Jens Stoltenberg, and the government made a shift from being a labour to a conservative government. It has administrative subdivisions on two levels, known as counties (fylke) and municipalities (kommuner). The Sámi people have a certain amount of self-determination and influence over traditional territories through the Sámi Parliament and the Finnmark Act. Norway maintains close ties with the European Union and its member countries (despite rejecting full EU membership in two referenda), as well as with the United States. Norway participates with United Nations forces in international missions, notably in Afghanistan, Kosovo, Sudan, and Libya. Norway is a founding member of the United Nations, NATO, the Council of Europe, and the Nordic Council; a member of the European Economic Area, the WTO and the OECD; and is also a part of the Schengen Area.
The country has the fourth-highest per capita income in the world on the World Bank and IMF lists, as well as ninth-highest on a more comprehensive CIA list. On a per-capita basis, it is the world\'s largest producer of oil and natural gas outside the Middle East, From 2001 to 2006, and then again from 2009 to 2012, Norway had the highest Human Development Index ranking in the world. Norway has also topped the Legatum Prosperity Index for the last five years. The OECD ranks Norway third in social mobility and fourth on the 2013 equalized Better Life Index. From 2010 to 2012, Norway was classified as the most democratic country by the Democracy Index.
    </string>
    <string name="starry_night">Swipe to see more pictures\n\n
        Starry Night (Dutch: De sterrennacht) is a painting by the Dutch post-impressionist artist Vincent van Gogh. Painted in June 1889, it depicts the view outside of his sanitarium room window at Saint-Rémy-de-Provence (located in southern France) at night, although it was painted from memory during the day. It has been in the permanent collection of the Museum of Modern Art in New York City, part of the Lillie P. Bliss Bequest, since 1941. The painting is among Van Gogh\'s most well-known works and marks a decisive turn towards greater imaginative freedom in his art.\n
        Perhaps no other painting in Western Art has enjoyed such a varying array of intriguing interpretations. Academic theories tend towards two schools: the literal and the literary. The literal includes both he painted what he saw and the hallucinatory genius arguments (as an individual\'s hallucinations are indistinguishable from real life) while the literary suggest that inspiration blossomed from some written source; most often cited for van Gogh\'s Starry Night are The Bible, Walt Whitman and Victor Hugo.\n
Legendary 20th century art historian Albert Boime is generally credited with the best literal theory by proving, in conjunction with three Astronomer colleagues at UCLA the position of the stars from van Gogh\'s window in the asylum at Saint-Rémy-de-Provence at 4 a.m. on June 19, 1889, the day van Gogh wrote his brother that he had completed the painting. In a 1985 lecture to the American Astronomical Society, Boime compared the positions of the moon and Venus that night and showed that they corresponded to the positions of the celestial objects in the painting. While Boime and his lead astronomer, Charles Whitney agreed the large star above the horizon is the Morning Star, they failed to agree on the arrangement of the other stars. Boime claimed they constituted the constellation of Aries, while Whitney argued it was Cygnus. Boime further attempted to make the argument that van Gogh had likely seen an image of a spiral galaxy from Camille Flammarion\'s Astronomie populaire, in an attempt to explain the existence of van Gogh\'s celestial spiral jetty. In his 800-plus existing letters, however, van Gogh makes no mention of ever reading Flammarion.\n
As to the leading literary theories: those about The Bible range from van Gogh painting a passage out of Genesis 37 describing a dream of Joseph to an apocalyptic depiction out of the twelfth book of Revelation to a sublimated Christ in the Garden of Gethsemane;bwhile those from Whitman attempt to correlate the painting\'s poetic vision within Song of Myself; and (what has been mistakenly attributed to Hugo\'s Les Miserables) as an inspired depiction of God as a lighthouse in eclipse.\n
This bevy of interpretations has helped keep van Gogh\'s Starry Night firmly within the discussions and lively debates of both public and academic art history.
    </string>
</resources>
